Who's up for a close encounter?
Paul is a adventure, comedy, science fiction film directed by Greg Mottola.
For the past 60 years, a space-traveling smart-ass named Paul has been locked up in
a top-secret military base, advising world leaders about his kind.
But when he worries he’s outlived his usefulness and the dissection table is drawing
uncomfortably close, Paul escapes on the first RV that passes by his compound in Area 51.
Fortunately, it contains the two earthlings who are most
likely to rescue and harbor an alien on the run.
Graeme Willy, played by Simon Pegg.
Clive Gollings, played by Nick Frost.
Paul (voice), played by Seth Rogen.
Special Agent Lorenzo Zoil, played by Jason Bateman.
Ruth Buggs, played by Kristen Wiig.
Haggard, played by Bill Hader.
Paul is a 2011 British science fiction comedy road film directed by
Greg Mottola and written by Simon Pegg and Nick Frost.
Starring Pegg and Frost, with the voice and motion capture of Seth Rogen as Paul,
the film follows two science fiction geeks who come across an alien.
Together, they help the alien escape from the Secret Service agents who
are pursuing him so that he can return to his home planet.
The film is a parody of other science-fiction films, especially those of
Steven Spielberg, as well as of science fiction fandom in general.
Paul had its world premiere at the Empire Leicester Square in London on 7 February 2011, and was
theatrically released in the United Kingdom on 14 February, by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office success,
grossing $98 million worldwide on a $40 million budget.
The film explores themes of san diego, california, alien,
burlesque, area 51, alien space craft.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.